I'd like to welcome you all to this important event,
我想欢迎大家参加这个重要的活动，
and I would also like to apologize to those among your friends, relatives,
同时，我也想对你们的朋友、亲戚，
and colleagues who could not be here today as the auditorium sold out in a matter of hours.
以及同事们因礼堂门票在几小时内售罄而无法到场的情况表示歉意。
My name is Joffrey Clarkfield.
我的名字是乔弗里·克拉克菲尔德。
It is my privilege to be the executive director of the Speakers Action Group,
我很荣幸能够成为演讲者行动组织的执行董事，
and I would like to thank founding president Shirley Ann Haber and our new president Irving Weisdorf and all the volunteers who have worked so hard to make this event happen.
我想感谢创始总裁雪莉·安·哈伯和我们的新总裁欧文·韦斯多夫，以及所有辛勤工作使这个活动成为可能的志愿者们。
I would also like to thank our partner organization, the Masood Freedom Foundation,
我还想感谢我们的合作组织，马苏德自由基金会，
and the Council for Muslims Facing Tomorrow,
以及面向未来的穆斯林委员会，
who are the joint sponsors of this event.
他们是本次活动的联合赞助商。
The Speakers Action Group in particular, and its supporting groups,
特别是演讲者行动组织及其支持团体，
is dedicated to the fight against anti-Semitism and racism.
致力于反对反犹太主义和种族主义的斗争。
But without freedom of speech, there could be no fight against anti-Semitism or racism.
但是，如果没有言论自由，就无法与反犹太主义或种族主义作斗争。
For we need freedom of speech to defend our rights.
因为我们需要言论自由来捍卫我们的权利。
And as we will hear today,
正如我们今天将听到的，
freedom of speech is most threatened where, ironically, it should be most free in the media, in the colleges, in the universities of this country,
在媒体、学院、本国的大学以及其他民主国家，
as well as in other democracies.
言论自由最受威胁的地方，讽刺地，应该是最自由的。
I would like to introduce the emcee for this afternoon,
我想介绍今天下午的主持人，
Faith Goldie from the Rebel Media,
来自反叛媒体的费斯·戈尔迪，
an organization that is at the forefront of the fight for free speech in this country.
一个在这个国家为言论自由奋斗的前沿组织。
I'd like her to introduce our two distinguished speakers,
我希望她能介绍我们的两位杰出演讲者，
Professor Jordan Peterson and Dr. Norman Deutch.
乔丹·彼得森教授和诺曼·德奇博士。
Faith, thank you so much for being here today.
费斯，非常感谢你今天能来这里。
He's been a dishwasher, a gas jockey, a bartender,
他曾经是洗碗工、加油站员工、酒吧服务员，
a short order cook, a beekeeper, a plywood mill laborer, and a railway line worker.
快餐厨师、养蜂人、胶合板厂工人，以及铁路工人。
But today, Professor Jordan B. Peterson is best known for his work in the academic world.
但今天，乔丹·B·彼得森教授最为人所知的是他在学术界的工作。
He has published more than 100 scientific papers transforming the modern understanding of personality
他发表了超过100篇科学论文，彻底改变了现代对个性的理解
and revolutionizing the psychology of religion with his now classic book, Maps of Meaning, The Architecture of Belief.
并以他现已成为经典的书籍《意义的地图：信仰的架构》彻底革新了宗教心理学。
As a Harvard professor, he was nominated for the prestigious Levinson Teaching Prize.
作为哈佛大学的教授，他被提名为著名的莱文森教学奖。
Now at the University of Toronto,
现在在多伦多大学，
he is regarded by students as one of their truly life-changing teachers.
他被学生们视为他们真正改变生活的老师之一。
And I think that I speak for a great deal of people in this room and, frankly, across the country when I say,
我认为我代表了在座的许多人，坦白说，全国各地的人们，当我说，
you needn't be one of Professor Peterson's students to have been enlightened and inspired by that eight-pound universe between his ears,
你不需要成为彼得森教授的学生，就已经被他那颗重八磅的大脑以及他的勇气而启发和鼓舞，
Most recently, Dr. Peterson became the centre of an ongoing national controversy for refusing to abide by the University of Toronto's attempt to put very specific words into his mouth
最近，彼得森博士因拒绝遵守多伦多大学试图将非常具体的词汇强加于他口中的尝试，
when they ordered professors comply with the gender pronouns policy.
当他们命令教授们遵守性别代词政策时，成为了一场持续的全国性争议的中心。
Dr. Peterson's vivid dissent over language politics and the political agenda behind it
彼得森博士对语言政治及其背后的政治议程的鲜明异议，
has seen him threatened and shouted down by snowflake students and the academic hierarchy alike.
致使他被大学的学生和学术阶层威胁和叫嚷。
A result of his public views on how political correctness violates freedom of speech and academic freedom in the West,
由于他对政治正确如何侵犯西方言论自由和学术自由的公开观点，
Professor Peterson has become a cultural icon for liberty lovers,
彼得森教授已成为自由爱好者的文化偶像，
and a long-awaited obstruction to the wayfarers on the long march of the institutions.
也是人们期待已久的机构长征路上的绊脚石。
Please join me in welcoming Dr. Jordan B. Peterson.
请与我一起欢迎乔丹·B·彼得森博士。
So about three months ago, I sat in my office at night.
大约三个月前，我晚上坐在我的办公室里。
I wasn't really sleeping very well because my mind was running.
我当时真的睡得不是很好，因为我的脑子一直在运转。
And it was running because I had just read some policy documents on the Ontario Human Rights Commission website in relationship to Bill C-16.
之所以这样，是因为我刚在安大略人权委员会网站上阅读了一些关于C-16法案的政策文件。
And, at the same time, I had heard that the University of Toronto HR and Equity Vice-President had decided to make anti-unconscious bias training mandatory for her staff,
同时，我听说多伦多大学的人力资源和平等副总裁决定让她的员工必须接受反无意识偏见训练，
which I find appalling, and still find appalling.
这让我感到震惊，现在想起来仍然觉得震惊。
And I would recommend that if any of you are asked or required to have your unconscious biases adjusted that
我建议，如果有人要求或强制你调整你的无意识偏见，
you might note to yourself that by agreeing to do so you have agreed that you're guilty and I wouldn't recommend that
你可能会注意到，通过同意这样做，你已经同意你是有罪的，我不建议这样做
Anyways, I was mostly trying to straighten out my thoughts on these issues
无论如何，我主要是试图澄清我对这些问题的思考
You know and and that's usually what I do when I speak you know you know because and I have a good Reputation as a speaker,
你知道，这通常是我讲话时所做的，因为我有作为一个演讲者的良好声誉，
and I think there's two reasons for that one is I don't ever speak to a group I always speak to individuals, I'm not speaking to the group.
我认为这有两个原因，一个是我从不对群体讲话，我总是对个人讲话，我不是对群体讲话。
I'm speaking to individual people, and I'm not telling you what's right, because I don't know what's right.
我是在对个人讲话，我不是在告诉你什么是对的，因为我不知道什么是对的。
What I'm trying to do is to formulate my thoughts more clearly,
我尝试做的是更清楚地表达我的思想，
and it's helpful to do that in speech, even in front of an audience, because it's a dialogue with an audience.
即使在观众面前通过演讲来做这件事也是有帮助的，因为这是与观众的对话。
You know, if you watch the individuals, then they, you can tell if they're following you, or whether,
你知道，如果你观察个体，那么他们，你可以知道他们是否跟随你，或者，
mostly whether they're following you, if they can understand the line of the argumentation
大多数情况下他们是否跟随你，如果他们能理解论证的线索
and some of them will be shaking their heads and some of them will be nodding
其中一些人会摇头，一些人会点头
and you know some of them will be looking puzzled in which case you have to kind of reformulate
你知道一些人会看起来困惑，在这种情况下你必须重新表达
and so and that's that's how I that's how to think
这就是我思考的方式
and when you're speaking to people it's okay to tell them what you know but better to show them how you think
当你对人们讲话时，告诉他们你所知道的是可以的，但更好的是向他们展示你是如何思考的
and that means you're going to stumble around like an idiot some of the time because you're trying to grapple with things
这意味着你有时会像个笨蛋一样摸索，因为你正在尝试解决问题
and what I try to do for my students is to to model the process of grappling with things,
我尝试为我的学生做的是模拟解决问题的过程，
because that's what you do when you think
因为这就是你思考时所做的
and Norman pointed out that you can be right or you can try to get smarter and to be right
诺曼指出，你可以是对的，或者你可以试着变得更聪明，
then you convince people that you're right but to try to get smarter you find out why you're wrong
如果你是对的，你就说服别人你是对的，但如果你想变得更聪明，你就得找出你错在哪里
and so I decided a long time ago that one of the ways to deal with my authoritarian tendencies
所以很久以前我决定，防止我自己变得刚愎自用的方式是，
let's say was to make friends with what I don't know instead of what I do know
可以说，是与我不知道的东西交朋友，而不是我知道的东西
and that's a whole different way of looking at the world, you know,
这是一种完全不同的看待世界的方式，你知道，
and it's it's got its pain because you know, you're always trying to figure out more or less why you're a biased moron
这其中有它的痛苦，因为你知道，你总是在尝试弄清楚为什么你是一个有偏见的白痴
and that's a very long list of that's a very you have a very long list of reasons for that
这会是一个很长的清单，上面会列着很多原因
and then you have to find out why you're wrong
然后你必须找出你为什么错了
and as a short-term mechanism for attaining psychological stability I wouldn't recommend it but as a long-term process
作为获得心理稳定的短期机制，我不推荐这样做，但作为一个长期过程
where you're trying to make things work better in the medium to long term, then it's the only way,
当你试图在中长期内让事情变得更好时，那就是唯一的方式，
but you know, it's easy to sacrifice the future for the present, although it's kind of the reverse of the way you should do things.
但你知道，牺牲未来换取现在是容易的，虽然这与你应该做事的方式恰恰相反。
So anyways, I made these videos, pretty amateur videos, and you know,
无论如何，我制作了这些视频，相当业余的视频，你知道，
the lighting wasn't very good, and there was a bunch of things wrong with them,
灯光不是很好，有很多问题，
but one of the things I've been wondering about for the last three months is just what what happens like what's going on here.
但过去三个月我一直在想的一个问题就是发生了什么，这里到底是怎么回事。
This is crazy and I've been accused of a lot of things, some of which are no doubt true
这太疯狂了，我被指控了很多事情，当然其中有一些是真的
but I've been accused of being a racist and being a transphobe and what else profiteering
但我被指责为种族主义者、恐跨性别者，还有什么，从中牟利之人
and I guess the other one was scare mongering.
我猜另一个是制造恐慌。
Yeah, that's the other one scare mongering and so of course I've been wondering
是的，另一个是制造恐慌，所以我当然一直在想
if those things are true because it's not like you know,
这些指控是否属实，因为你知道，
my heart is as pure as the driven snow hardly and everyone has biases and all of that so
我的心像被风吹过的雪一样纯净，每个人都有偏见，这一切都是如此
and I also…… Well this unfolded had a group of friends who were definitely critics
这一切发生时，我也有一群朋友，他们绝对是批评者
who were watching everything I was doing and you know letting me know pretty forthrightly when I was being arrogant
他们关注着我所做的一切，当我表现得傲慢时，
and when I was look kind of disheveled and when my arguments weren't as clear as they could be
当我看起来有些凌乱，以及我的论点不如它们本可以清晰时，他们会非常直接地告诉我
and so and these were smart people and their comments were very incisive
这些都是聪明人，他们的评论非常尖锐
and then of course I had all the blowback, and I was paying attention to it,
然后当然我遭受了所有的强烈反响，我在关注它，
because, Well, you should pay attention to such things and so and I do pay attention to things,
因为，嗯，你应该关注这些事情，所以我确实在关注，
that's the thing I actually pay attention to things and
那就是我实际上在关注事情，
if I'm embroiled in a controversy, even if it's a like problem in my home,
如果我卷入一场争议，即使它像我家里的问题一样，
I try to get to the damn bottom of it
我试图弄清楚它的真相
The bottom of things is not a pretty place to look
事情的最根本的层面并不好看
And so you know when you're arguing with someone at home
所以你知道，当你在家里与某人争论时
even someone you love
即使是你爱的人
You'll notice that your argument can get out of hand a pretty quick, so if you're arguing with your wife or your husband
你会注意到你的争论很快就会失控，所以如果你在和你的妻子或丈夫争论
You know it depends on how volatile you are of course
你知道这取决于你有多容易爆发
But you know you start arguing about some little thing and then
但你知道，你开始争论一些小事，然后
You can't understand pretty quick that it's actually not about that little thing at all that little thing is associated with
你很快就会明白，实际上根本不是因为那个小事，那个小事与
You know a little bigger thing underneath that and maybe that's associated with even a bigger thing under that
你知道，一个更大的事情有关，也许那个更大的事情下面还有更大的事情
soon you're taking each other apart for assuming you've been married for 20 years for all the stupid things you've done to each other over the last 20 years
很快你们就会因为假设你们已经结婚20年了，在过去的20年里彼此做过的所有愚蠢的事情而互相攻击
And it doesn't have to end there, and that's not pleasant.
而且不必在那里结束，那并不愉快。
It's really hard to bind a conversation So it doesn't go everywhere,
让一次对话保持在轨道上，不至于偏离主题真的很难，
so one thing you can do if you're talking to someone about something you disagree with someone you love,
所以如果你正在和某人谈论你不同意的事情，与你爱的人，
you can tell them a bunch of good things about what they've been doing which you actually believe and then just say well, but there's this little problem here
你可以告诉他们很多你真正相信的关于他们一直在做的事情，
and I just like it adjusted in a minor way and maybe that'll you know sort things out a bit between us
我只是希望以一种小的方式调整一下，也许这能在我们之间稍微解决一些问题
and then maybe you don't fall into that stupid pit
然后也许你就不会掉进那个愚蠢的坑里
which is really easy to fall into and you know which certainly can lead to
掉进去真的很容易，你知道，这当然会导致离婚等事情，所以问题的很大一部分总是这到底是关于什么
Well, I've been asking myself that question for a long long time because I've been interested in
嗯，我已经问自己这个问题很长时间了，因为我对权威主义冲突、暴行和极权主义的兴趣远远超过任何理智的人应该有的兴趣时间，并且
You know and then this and then this all came up, and I thought okay, okay, okay?
你知道，然后这一切都出现了，我想好吧，好吧，好吧？
It's like all right Well, you know, am I a bigot and a transphobe?
就像好吧，你知道，我是一个偏执者和恐跨性别者吗？
Well, I probably have my biases because people tend to have in-group biases, you know, and that's associated, by the way, with compassion.
嗯，我可能有我的偏见，因为人们倾向于有群体内偏见，你知道，这其实是与同情心相关的。
Just so you know it, because one of the things compassion does is make you much strongly, much more strongly bound to your in-group, you know.
只是让你知道，因为同情心做的其中一件事是让你与你的群体更加紧密地联系在一起。
It's like a mother is compassionate because she loves her baby, and she loves the baby more than other things that aren't the baby, obviously.
就像一位母亲之所以有同情心是因为她爱她的孩子，并且她爱她的孩子更甚于爱其他的事情，显然。
And so actually compassion is one of the main sources of in-group bias which is something for the compassion warriors to think about for like three-fifths of a second.
所以实际上，同情心是群体内偏见的主要来源之一，这是同情战士们需要思考一下的。
There's there's nothing less compassionate to you than a mother grizzly bear protecting her cubs
没有什么比灰熊妈妈保护她的幼崽更富有同情心了
And so you should think about that when you think about empathy for a minute because empathy is by no means an untrammeled moral virtue
所以当你思考同理心时应该考虑这一点，因为同理心绝不是一个完全的道德美德
In fact it's responsible and can be responsible for absolutely atrocious actions
实际上，它是负有责任的，并且可能对绝对残暴的行为负责
It depends on who you're empathizing with you know and if you're empathizing with someone that you regard as an infantilized victim
这取决于你同情谁，你知道的，如果你同情的是某个被视为弱小无助的受害者
then you automatically snap into a frame of mind where everyone who might be oppressing that infantilized victim is a predatory parasite,
那么你自动就会进入一种心态，认为任何可能压迫这个弱小无助受害者的人都是恶意的剥削者，
and you're not very bloody empathetic to them I can tell you so that's a big problem
而你对他们就没有什么同情心，我可以告诉你，这是个大问题。
Anyways with regards to this scare mongering issue
无论如何，关于这个制造恐慌的问题
so yeah yeah biased yeah probably and blind definitely like more than more than you might expect no I don't think so
所以，是的，是的，有偏见，是的，可能有，而且绝对是盲目的，比你可能预期的还要盲目。不，我不这么认为。
and one of the things  that actually protected me through all this was that you know I've actually tried to come to terms with the evil that lurks in human hearts particularly my own
真正保护我度过这一切的一件事是，你知道我实际上已经试图接受潜伏在人类内心的邪恶，尤其是我自己的内心
and I have 500 hours of lectures on that online if anybody you know has the bizarre desire to pound their way through them they can more or less think figure out what I think
我有500小时的讲座在线上，如果有人有奇怪的愿望想要看它们，他们可以多少了解我在想什么
because I said 500 of hours of it publicly and so I didn't feel too bad about my level of bigotry or hatred you know
因为我公开说了500个小时，所以我对我的偏见或仇恨的程度并不感到太糟
I think you could probably infer that by watching the video
我认为你可能通过观看视频可以推断出来
so it's kind of protected on that front and then there was the scaremongering issue
所以在那方面我自己已经有了心理建设，然后就是制造恐慌的问题，那是个好问题，那真的很难
because you know if you look at Bill C-16 it just kind of looks like
因为你知道，如果你看C-16法案，它看起来像是我们正在扩大保护范围，以保护到另一个受压迫的群体，这其实不准确，因为性别认同
by the way you know gender expression that's not a group
顺便说一下，你知道，性别表达，那不是一个群体
I'd like just like to point that out because terminological accuracy actually matters
我想指出这一点，因为术语的准确性确实很重要
So we've extended legal protection to fashion essentially
所以我们本质上已经将法律保护扩展到流行领域
and you can say, Well maybe I'm you know being a bit intransigent about that, but I read the damn policies, and I don't think I am
你可以说，也许我在这方面有点固执，但我读了那些该死的政策，我不认为我固执
And that's not a group so that's an indication of the muddle-headedness behind the legislation
那不是一个群体，这表明了立法背后的混乱
And then the federal government the department of justice did say on their own website
然后联邦政府，司法部在他们自己的网站上说
that they were going to interpret that law in light of the policies of the Ontario Human Rights Commission
他们将根据安大略人权委员会的政策解释那部法律
and so, fine man go to the Ontario Human Rights Commission if they haven't taken the policies off yet
所以，去吧，如果他们还没有撤下政策，去安大略人权委员会看看
and read what they're up to and if that if you agree with that well good agree with it
读读他们在做什么，如果你同意，那么好，同意吧
But I would suspect that if you agree with it you don't you didn't understand it or you're up to something and that comes to the next part.
但我怀疑如果你同意这点，那么你要么没有理解它，要么你有所图谋，这就引出了下一个部分。
What are what are we really talking about here?
我们到底在讨论什么？
Well, so we could be talking about my biases and my proclivity to scare monger,
嗯，我们可能在讨论我的偏见和我散布恐慌的倾向，
and you know fair enough but here's some reasons we're not and one is that I have all those lectures online and
你知道，公平地说，但这里有一些理由说明我们不是，其中一个是我所有的讲座都在线上，
You know believe me if there would have been a phrase in any of them that indicated that there was something even vaguely morally corrupt about me.
你知道，相信我，如果其中任何一个讲座里有哪怕是隐约表明我道德上有问题的话语。
It would have been paraded around as evidence.
它肯定会被当作证据到处传播。
You can be sure of that, so that's kind of a relief
你可以确定这一点，所以这有点让人宽慰
you know, I did a lot of soul-searching in the last couple of months and it's not like I'm without my problems,
你知道，过去几个月我做了很多自我反省，不是说我没有问题，
but anyways, so what is this about?
但无论如何，这是关于什么的？
well we'll say hopefully it's not about me because that'd be stupid and so what what's going on?
嗯，我们希望这不是关于我，因为那会很愚蠢。那么，究竟发生了什么？
Why are all these people watching these videos these things I made just to figure out what it was that I was thinking
为什么这么多人在观看这些视频，这些我仅仅是想弄清楚我当时在想什么而制作的东西？
because I couldn't sleep one night and because I'm not very damn happy about that unconscious bias stuff, which I regard is absolutely reprehensible
因为有一天晚上我睡不着，而且我对那些潜意识偏见的东西非常不满，我认为那绝对是可恶的
that you could be held guilty for your implicit perceptions.
想象一下，你因为你的隐性感知而被认定有罪。
Think about that, God, they use that test as a diagnostic test.
想想看，天哪，他们把那个测试作为一种诊断测试。
You know, it doesn't meet the criteria for reliability and validity that you'd use for a diagnostic test.
你知道，它不符合你会用于诊断测试的可靠性和有效性的标准。
It doesn't produce the same results one time after another, and you can use it to target anybody.
它不会一次又一次产生相同的结果，你可以用它来针对任何人。
And so go along with it if you want, and just see what happens.
所以，如果你想继续相信它，就看看会发生什么吧。
Anyways, so I've been thinking about this, like, what's going on?
无论如何，所以我一直在思考，像，究竟发生了什么？
Why the outcry?
为什么会有这样的抗议？
You know you think well professor Peterson got his 15 minutes of fame
你知道你会想，嗯，彼得森教授得到了他的 15 分钟的名气（译注：“15分钟的名声”是指一个人短暂地受到公众的广泛关注和讨论，这个概念最初是由艺术家安迪·沃霍尔提出的，他说“在未来，每个人都将有15分钟的名气。” ）
it's like I had my 15 minutes of you know, trivial fame several times in my life and
就像我一生中几次得到了那么十五分钟的，你知道，微不足道的名声
There's some good things about it But I am despite what you might think a rather private person
关于它有一些好的方面，但不管你怎么想，我实际上是一个相当注重隐私的人，
so it's not like I'm particularly enjoying it, but I thought something you know when I made those videos.
所以我并不是特别享受它，但我想到了一些事情，你知道，当我制作那些视频的时候。
I thought this is something I learned from reading mythology
我想这是我从阅读神话中学到的东西
if you have to fight a dragon you should go to its lair before it comes to your village
如果你必须与龙战斗，你应该在它来到你的村庄之前去它的巢穴
And so people think of what I did is courageous,
所以人们认为我所做的是勇敢的，
and I don't think that's right I just think that I can see danger coming and you get to pick you get to pick your anxiety
而我不认为那是对的，我只是认为我能看到危险来临，你可以选择，你可以选择你的焦虑
I could either be anxious about speaking or I could be anxious about not speaking and so I chose to be anxious about speaking
我可以选择对表达感到焦虑，也可以选择对不表达感到焦虑，所以我选择了对表达感到焦虑
And that's not exactly courage.
这并不完全是勇气。
It's more like common sense, but that assumes that you're looking into the future
这更像是常识，但这假设你在看向未来
So you might say, well what gives me any special power to look into the future,
所以你可能会说，嗯，什么给了我任何特殊的能力来预见未来，
and here that's a good question and my god only knows what's going to happen in the next few years.
这是一个好问题，天知道接下来几年会发生什么。
You know I did read today
你知道，我今天读到了
This is cool
这很酷
thousand people will be lifted out of absolute poverty today, and three hundred thousand more will be connected to electricity.
今天将有一千人脱离绝对贫困，另外三十万人将接入电力。
And we're knocking poverty rates around the world down faster by a huge margin than we ever have in human history.
我们正在以前所未有的速度降低全球的贫困率。
There was an article in the New York Times today called, Why 2016 Was the Best Year Ever.
今天纽约时报有一篇文章，标题是《为什么2016年是有史以来最好的一年》。
It's really worth reading.
读起来真的很值得。
I concluded the same thing.
我得出了同样的结论。
I worked for a UN committee a couple of years ago and I was looking at, you know, what was going to happen down the road.
几年前我为联合国一个委员会工作，我在考虑，你知道，未来会发生什么。
And everything I I kept reading was well, wow, we're getting rid of polio.
而我一直读到的是，哇，我们正在消灭脊髓灰质炎。
We're getting rid of elephantiasis, which you really don't want to have We're getting rid of Guinea worm.
我们正在消灭象皮病，这是你绝对不想得的病，我们正在消灭几内亚虫病。
We're getting rid of polio.
我们正在消灭脊髓灰质炎。
We're knocking malaria back into the swamps from where it comes we're lifting people out of poverty.
我们正在将疟疾赶回它来的沼泽，我们正在帮助人们摆脱贫困。
It's like man, we're doing a lot of good things You'd sure never guess that by the way, we treat ourselves
就像，伙计，我们在做很多好事。从我们对待自己的方式来看，你绝对猜不到这一点
So anyways, so what's going on?
所以，究竟发生了什么？
Okay, so I thought well I better think about this.
好吧，所以我想我最好好好想想这件事。
I've been thinking about a long time.
我已经想了很长时间了。
So So, you know, the right wing is really hard on the Frankfurt School, you know, on the Frankfurt School,
所以，你知道，右翼对法兰克福学派真的很严厉，你知道，对法兰克福学派，
where these kind of neo-Marxist guys who combined Marxism with Freudianism in the 1940s,
这些人是20世纪40年代将Marxism主义与弗洛伊德主义结合的新Marxism主义者，
and they weren't avowed neo-Marxists, you know, so it's not like I'm making an accusation.
他们是公开的新Marxism主义者，你知道，所以这并不像是我在做指控。
And they were kind of anti-system type people,
他们是那种反体制的人，
and all of that, but I think to lay what's happening at the universities and in brought at in the broader culture itself
所有这些，但我认为将大学和更广泛的文化中发生的事情归咎于法兰克福学派是不够的
at the feet of the Frankfurt School is insufficient
我真的认为这主要是法国知识分子的后果
I really think that it's primarily a consequence of the French intellectuals
显然这是一种简化，他们是20世纪70年代初从Marxism主义中崛起的
and produced post-modernism now the thing about the post-modernist types is they're nested inside Marxism
并产生了后现代主义。现在关于后现代主义者的事情是，他们嵌套在Marxism主义内部
they say that straight out I'm not inventing this you read Derrida, who's like the the Joker at the at the head of the postmodernist movement
他们直接这么说，我不是在编造，你读德里达，他就像是后现代主义运动的领头人
and I mean Joker because he's he's he's an intellectual clown and that doesn't mean he's stupid, because he is not stupid not at all
我之所以说他是小丑，是因为他是一个智识上的小丑，这并不意味着他愚蠢，因为他一点也不愚蠢
these people are not stupid they know exactly what they're doing
这些人不愚蠢，他们确切知道自己在做什么
they know precisely what they're doing they're a hell of a lot more educated about what they're doing than you are,
他们非常清楚自己在做什么，他们比你更了解自己在做什么，
unless you happen to be one of them and they mean exactly what they say
除非你恰好是他们中的一员，他们确切地表达了自己的意图
just like people always do when they tell you what they're going to do or they write it down.
就像人们总是在告诉你他们打算做什么或者把它写下来时那样。
And they say straight out on their websites,
他们在他们的网站上直言不讳地说，
say the women's studies websites,
比如说女性研究的网站，
we think the patriarchy is an oppressive structure that should be broken down to its core.
我们认为父权制是一个压迫性结构，应该被彻底拆解。
And they mean core conceptions.
他们的意思是核心概念。
It's not just social.
这不仅仅是社会层面的。
It's linguistic, philosophical, and attitudinal.
它是语言的、哲学的、态度的。
It should be broken down, wiped out,
它应该被拆解、消除，
and restructured from the bottom up.
并且从底层重构。
And they mean that.
他们是认真的。
So when it's not accidental any of this and I know it sounds like a bloody paranoid conspiracy theory but you know,
所以，这一切都不是偶然的，我知道这听起来像是一个疯狂的阴谋论，但是你知道，
I've always been of the idea especially from reading young that ideas people don't have ideas ideas have people and these are powerful ideas
我一直认为，尤其是从读荣格开始，人们没有观念，观念拥有人们，而这些是有力的观念
There's a good book called explaining post-modernism that I might recommend by a guy named named Stephen RC Hicks
有一本不错的书叫《解释后现代主义》，我可能会推荐，作者是史蒂芬·R·C·希克斯
and his first chapter which isn't very long is a good introduction to political correctness,
他的第一章并不长，是对政治正确性的一个好的介绍，
but so why do I think this is about about that?
但是，为什么我认为这是关于那个的呢？
Well, here's my reasons I mean, it doesn't seem to be about me
嗯，这里是我的理由，我意思是，这似乎不是关于我
I think all I did actually was actually I made the general specific
我认为我所做的实际上是将一般的变成了特定的
Okay, which is kind of what you have to do if you really want to make a point a point
好吧，这在某种程度上是你如果真的想要表达一个观点必须做的事情
Right.
对吧。
That's one place if you want to make a point and my point was I'm not saying made-up words
如果你想要表达一个观点，我的观点是我不会说那些由后现代新Marxism主义者创造的词语，因为我鄙视他们所代表的一切
and so I'm not using those damn words and that's that and it's it's not like I have something against transgender people
所以我不会使用那些该死的词汇，就是这样，这并不是说我对跨性别人群有什么偏见
I'm sure some of them are lovely people and some of them aren't
我敢肯定他们中的一些人是可爱的人，有些则不是
and so they can do whatever they want as far as I'm concerned as long as they don't
所以就我而言，他们可以做任何他们想做的事情，只要他们不……
they can do whatever they want as far as I'm concerned,
就我而言，他们可以做任何他们想做的事情，
as long as I'm not forced to go along with the most radical representatives of them who don't even speak for them.
只要我不被迫去顺从他们中最激进的代表，这些代表甚至不代表他们自己。
Anyways, I've got like 20 letters from transsexual people supporting what I've done, and like none opposing it.
无论如何，我收到了大约20封来自变性人的信，他们支持我所做的事情，反对的则没有。
You know, one of the things that's kind of cool is I've only got three hate letters.
你知道，有一件事情挺酷的，我只收到了三封仇恨信。
I thought three?
我想，三封？
Jesus, you guys aren't trying very hard and I've got like a thousand letters of support
天啊，你们这是没怎么努力啊。而我收到了大约一千封支持信
and if you go on YouTube where I'm radically overrepresented and you look at the comments
如果你去YouTube上看，在那里我被极度过分地代表了，
and the likes and the dislikes it's about the same ratio it's like likes to dislikes is like about a hundred to one
你看看评论以及点赞和不喜欢的比例，大致是相同的，大约是一百比一
and almost all the comments are positive which you know could easily be a selection bias and probably is
几乎所有的评论都是积极的，这当然很可能是选择偏差，但这仍然意味着
but you know it still means that there's quite a a few people who think that what I'm doing is sort of okay as far as they're concerned, and so that's important.
有相当一部分人认为我所做的在某种程度上是可以接受的，这很重要。
So anyways, we need to talk a little bit about postmodernism.
无论如何，我们需要稍微谈谈后现代主义。
Okay, so let's go back to France in the 19, end of the 1960s.
好的，那我们就回到1960年代末的法国。
So, and this is of course an oversimplification, and I'm sure I'm wrong about some of it, because
这当然是一种简化，我确信我在某些方面理解有误，因为
you know, it's not exactly my field of speciality, this sort of sociology.
你知道，这并非完全是我的专业领域，这种社会学。
I'm more of the scientist type, but... and if I read philosophy, I tend not to read second-rate philosophy,
我更像是科学家类型，但如果我读哲学，我倾向于不读二流的哲学，
and so I've tried to avoid the postmodernists to some degree,
因此我在某种程度上尝试避开后现代主义者，
because their ncoherency is one of the least of their sins, but they don't care about that.
因为他们自身的不一致是他们最轻的罪过之一，但他们并不关心这一点。
No, no, you've got to understand, man, that it's modernists and Enlightenment people and even traditionalists who care about coherency.
不，不，你得明白，关心一致性的是现代主义者、启蒙时代的人甚至是传统主义者。
The postmodernists don't believe in coherency, they don't believe in... and I'm not making this up.
后现代主义者不相信一致性，他们不相信……我并没有编造这个。
This is part of their philosophy.
这是他们哲学的一部分。
They don't believe in logic.
他们不相信逻辑。
You know, Derrida says straight out that Western society is phallo-logo-centric, by which he means male-centered and privileging the idea of logic.
你知道，德里达直言不讳地说西方社会是以男性为中心并且特权逻辑思维的。
Well, he doesn't buy any of that.
好吧，他不接受任何那些。
He doesn't think that there's a truth that's out there.
他不认为外面有什么真理存在。
He doesn't believe that individuals can reach any sort of truth by thinking.
他不相信个体可以通过思考达到任何形式的真理。
He certainly doesn't believe that we can move towards truth in dialogue, because that's dialogic, right?
他当然不相信我们可以通过对话接近真理，因为那是对话的，对吧？
There's none of that.
那是不存在的。
well, why don't the, why do the postmodern types keep other thinkers off the campus?
那么，为什么后现代主义者要把其他思想家拒之校园之外呢？
Well, it's not because they're afraid.
嗯，这不是因为他们害怕。
Well, although some of them are, but they use their fragility as a mask for their, you know, the underlying philosophical, their underlying philosophical and political interests.
虽然他们中的一些人确实感到害怕，但他们使用自己的脆弱性作为遮掩，掩盖他们的基础哲学和政治利益。
They do that fragmentarily.
他们这样做是零散的。
It's not like every social justice warrior is a, you know,
并不是每一个社会正义斗士都是，手持剑的后现代主义者，但这些想法在他们之间零散分布，就像分布在暴民中一样。
And if you put the whole mob together, you get the whole post-modernist thing happening at the same time, and that's how ideas have people, instead of the other way around.
如果你把整个暴民聚集在一起，你就会同时发生整个后现代主义的事情，这就是思想如何影响人们，而不是相反。
Anyways, forget about logic.
无论如何，忘记逻辑吧。
That's out the window.
那已经是过去的事了。
That's just a construct of Western society, and the whole point of the construct was to oppress other people, and to take their wealth,
那只是西方社会的一种构造，而这种构造的全部目的是压迫其他人，并夺取他们的财富，
and to privilege the people who live within that so-called logic system, so that they can justify to themselves and other people their their predator rapaciousness, straight and simple.
并使生活在所谓逻辑系统中的人获得特权，这样他们就可以向自己和其他人证明他们的掠夺性贪婪，直截了当。
And that's partly because postmodernism was influenced by Marxism.
这部分是因为后现代主义受到了Marxism主义的影响。
And of course, that's what the Marxists think about.
当然，这正是Marxism主义者所思考的。
Any situation where there's a,
任何存在权力地位差异的情况，处于顶端的人只是因为他们从底层的人那里偷走了一切。
let's call it a power status differential, the people at the top are only there because they've stole everything from the people at the bottom.
我们称之为权力地位差异，处于顶层的人只是因为他们从底层的人那里偷走了一切。
And so the Marxists in France realized
因此，法国的Marxism主义者意识到
by the end of 1960s thereabouts
大约在1960年代末
when even Jean-Paul Sartre finally figured out
即使是让-保尔·萨特最终也明白了
to be a communist probably wasn't acceptable given that the bloody Soviets had killed like 30 million people between 1919 and 1959 and the Maoists
成为一个共产主义者可能是不可接受的，鉴于那些血腥的Soviets在1919年到1959年间杀害了大约3000万人，
had done the same thing on a greater scale in China and then talk about North Korea and we can talk about……
而Maoists在CN也在更大规模上做了同样的事情，然后我们再谈谈北韩和我们可以讨论的......
students don't learn any of that in school anymore and even if they did they wouldn't want to listen to it
学生们在学校不再学习任何这些内容，即使他们学了，他们也不愿意听
when I tell my students in my second year psychology class about the Gulag archipelago hardly any of them know
当我在我的二年级心理学课上告诉我的学生们关于古拉格群岛，几乎没有人知道
well why is that well it's because they haven't been taught it why is that well
那为什么会这样呢？因为他们没有被教导。那为什么他们没有被教导呢？
see if you can figure it out all right so so anyways back to the postmodern types so you know it got to the point where there's just no way you
看看你能不能弄明白。好的，回到后现代主义者，你知道，到了某个地步，你就无法
could be a Marxist especially after Solzhenitsyn
尤其是在索尔仁尼琴之后，你就无法成为一个Marxism主义者了。
because Solzhenitsyn wrote this great book which is actually out of print for crying out loud
因为索尔仁尼琴写了这本伟大的书，居然已经绝版了，真是让人哭笑不得
which I've actually been able to popularize like mad over the last three months which is you know really mind-boggling
我实际上在过去三个月里疯狂地推广了这本书，这真是令人难以置信
and what Solzhenitsyn did in his genius manner
索尔仁尼琴以他的天才手法
because he's up there with Dostoevsky and Tolstoy like man that guy he's a towering intellect and a person of spectacular moral force
因为他与陀思妥耶夫斯基和托尔斯泰齐名，那个人，他是一个高瞻远瞩的智者，一个具有惊人道德力量的人
you know like he put himself on the line for that book he memorized it when he was in the in the prison camps
你知道，他为那本书冒了生命危险，他在监狱营地时把它记在脑子里
it's about it's three volumes that thick you know it's like 2,000 pages of
它大约是三卷那么厚，你知道，大概2000页的
someone screaming the smartest person you've ever met the wisest person you've ever met screaming in outrage for 2,000 pages
即使是你遇到过的最聪明的人，你遇到过的最有智慧的人，面对这2000页厚的书籍也会震惊
it's no bloody wonder it's out of print anyways what Solzhenitsyn did was take on this
难怪它绝版了。无论如何，索尔仁尼琴做的是挑战这个你经常听到激进左派关于communism主义、关于Marxism主义的说法。
They say, well that wasn't real Marxism.
他们说，那不是真正的Marxism主义。
It's like, okay, well how many countries do you need to disprove your thesis?
好吧，你需要多少个国家来证明你的论点是错的？
How many millions of people have to die before you might admit that you're wrong?
需要多少百万人死去你才可能承认你错了？
Well, obviously more than a hundred million
显然，超过一亿还不够
because that's the approximate total, that's probably an underestimate,
因为那是大约的总数，这可能还低估了，
but we'll be conservative because adding another 10 million doesn't really make that much difference.
但我们将保持保守，因为再增加1000万并没有太大区别。
So Solzhenitsyn took that argument apart, partly in his book Lenin in Zurich and then partly in the Gulag Archipelago book.
所以索尔仁尼琴部分在他的书《列宁在苏黎世》中，部分在《古拉格群岛》一书中拆解了这个论点。
Groundwork had already been laid for all that by Nietzsche who knew exactly what was coming in the 20th century
尼采已经为所有这些奠定了基础，他准确预见了20世纪将发生的事，
and by Dostoevsky who wrote a book called The Possessed back in like 1880
还有陀思妥耶夫斯基，他在大约1880年写了一本叫做《鬼魅》的书
where he outlined in painful detail the precise mindset that would produce the Russian Revolution like 30 years later.
在其中他详细概述了30年后会产生俄国革命的确切心态。
Amazing.
令人惊叹。
Tolstoy, as well, he knew what was coming.
托尔斯泰也知道即将发生的事。
It made him suicidal.
这让他有了自杀的念头。
He wrote in his confession that when
他在他的忏悔录中写道，当俄罗斯的传统观念与从西方涌入的启蒙观念之间发生了冲突
Enlightenment ideas sweeping in from the West, they blew his worldview apart, which was traditional religious,
他的世界观被彻底瓦解，这个世界观是传统的宗教观，
blew his worldview apart so badly that he was suicidal at the height of his fame.
瓦解得如此之严重，以至于在他名声达到顶峰时他有了自杀的念头。
Tolstoy knew what was going to come, too.
托尔斯泰也知道即将发生的事。
And so it's not like Solzhenitsyn was the only person who could see this, Orwell knew it.
所以并不是只有索尔仁尼琴能看到这一点，奥威尔也知道。
Malcolm Muggeridge knew it in the 1930s when he was noting that the Soviets
马尔科姆·马格里奇在1930年代就知道这一点，当时他注意到Soviets鉴于他们的阶级罪疚感观念，这在我看来很像白人特权或任何其他形式的种族主义
they used that doctrine to just round up all the kulaks they were the productive farmers and ship them off to Siberia
他们利用这一理论将所有的富农——他们是生产力农民——集中起来并送往西伯利亚
and then six million Ukrainians starved to death but you know they had too many Ukrainians anyway so it didn't really matter, so anyways back to the postmodern types well
然后六百万乌克兰人饿死了，但你知道，他们反正人多，所以这并不真的重要，所以无论如何回到后现代主义者，嗯
you know this all came was revealed in such painful detail
你知道，这一切都在如此痛苦的细节中被揭露
that even the kind of closed-minded ideologue that Norman referred to just quite couldn't couldn't quite muster up the moral courage to keep beaten the same damn drum
即使是诺曼提到的那种思想封闭的意识形态家也几乎无法鼓起道德勇气继续敲打同一个该死的鼓（译注：不断重复同一个观点或主张，尤其是以一种单调、坚持不懈的方式。）
so what they did instead being highly intelligent individuals was play a game of sleight of hand
所以他们所做的不是去变得更指挥，而是玩一个花招游戏
and transformed these Marxist presuppositions into post-modernism in the 1970s
并在1970年代将这些Marxism主义的前提转化为后现代主义
and the idea basically was well the working class isn't going to rise up and crush the bourgeoisie
基本的想法是，工人阶级不会起来推翻资产阶级
because first of all they're getting rich and that wasn't supposed to happen
首先，他们正在变富，这不是预期中的情况
and second well it sort of seemed to be a catastrophe when that occurred let's say in Russia
其次，当这种情况在俄罗斯发生时，似乎是一场灾难
and so maybe we won't do that anymore because the working class actually isn't buying into this either
所以也许我们不再那样做了，因为工人阶级实际上也不买账
which is also a problem having internalized their own oppression they wouldn't buy into this to the global myth of utopia
这也是个问题，他们内化了自己的压迫，不会相信这个全球乌托邦的神话
so maybe it's because they had some sense it's certainly possible but anyways the sleight of hand was
也许是因为他们有一些判断力，这当然是可能的，但无论如何，这个戏法是
oh well fine we'll just play a different oppressor versus oppressed game
好吧，我们就玩另一种压迫者与被压迫者的游戏
and we'll introduce identity politics it's like okay okay you're not being oppressed
我们将引入身份政治，就像，好吧，你不是因为你是工人阶级而被压迫，你是因为你是女性或者因为你的种族不在主流范式之内而被压迫，无论那可能是什么
or it's because of your sexual preference or your sexual identity
或者是因为你的性取向或性别认同
whatever places you in some manner outside the normative culture
无论是什么使你以某种方式位于规范文化之外
and you know the thing is the postmodernist
你知道，问题是后现代主义者
you might think well your culture is good for something it gives you a hierarchy of value
你可能会认为，嗯，你的文化有其价值，它给你一个价值层级
it rewards competent people it gives you a direction so you can climb up
它奖励有能力的人，给你一个方向，让你可以向上攀爬
because otherwise everything's leveled to nothing and then why do anything they don't care about any of that,
否则一切都平等到了无足轻重，那么为什么还要做任何事呢？他们不在乎这些，
they don't believe that there's any such thing as competence, they don't believe that there's any such thing as up.
他们不相信有能力这回事，他们不相信有向上这回事。
This is all, postmodernism wipes all of that out.
这一切，后现代主义都抹去了。
And so when the postmodernists analyze a text, all they care about is how it privileges the position of the author and who it impresses.
所以当后现代主义者分析一篇文本时，他们只关心它是如何提升作者的地位以及它是如何压迫别人的。
And that's the only thing they regard as real, and they don't believe in grand unifying narratives,
这是他们认为唯一真实的东西，他们不相信宏大的统一叙事，
they don't believe that there's a Canadian identity, they don't believe that there's an American identity,
他们不相信有加拿大身份，他们不相信有美国身份，
they don't believe that there's a Western identity,
他们不相信有西方身份，
they don't believe Value structures exist or if they are they're irreplaceable with some other value structure.
他们不相信价值结构存在，或者如果它们存在，它们可以被其他价值结构替代。
They certainly don't believe that they have any biological grounding that there's any such thing as a human being it's all socially constructed
他们当然不相信它们有任何生物学基础，没有所谓的人类存在，一切都是社会构建的
which is really convenient if what you want to do is be the author of an entirely social constructed
这非常方便，如果你想要的是成为一个完全社会构建的乌托邦的作者，你可以运行它，然后当Marxism主义者说那不是真正的Marxism主义时
what it really means and I've thought about this for a long time
这实际上意味着，我已经思考了很长时间
It's the most arrogant possible statement anyone could ever make it means if I would have been in Stalin's position
这是任何人可能做出的最傲慢的声明，即，“如果我处于Stalin的位置
I would have ushered in the damn utopia instead that instead of the genocidal massacres
我会迎来该死的乌托邦，而不是种族屠杀
because I understand the doctrine of Marxism and everything about me is good.
因为我理解Marxism主义的教义，而我自己是完全善良的。”
It's like well think again sunshine
但，再好好想想吧，朋友，你不懂它
You don't understand it and you're not that good and that the power was in your hands assuming you had the competence which you don't
你不懂，你也没那么好，假设你有那些能力，你也不会做得更好，即使你做到了，还会有其他人在你第一次尝试做好事时就在你背后射杀你。
And that's what happened to all the old guard who ran the damn revolution.
这就是所有那些管理革命的老一辈人发生的事情。
Stalin rounded them all up and shot them, along with their families and millions of other people.
Stalin把他们全部围捕起来并射杀，连同他们的家人和数百万其他人。
So even if you do happen to be that avatar of moral purity that you claim implicitly,
所以，即使你确实是你所声称的那种道德纯洁的化身，
the probability that you'd get to act out your goodness in relationship to those possessed by your ideology is zero.
你以自己的意识形态实践你的善意的可能性是零。
So it's just...
所以这只是……
So, you know, you think, well, why are these postmodernists doing what they're doing?
所以，你知道，你会想，后现代主义者为什么要这么做？
Why do they oppose the patriarchy?
他们为什么反对父权制？
Here's a question.
这里有个问题。
Why don't the feminists complain about Saudi Arabia?
为什么女权主义者不抱怨沙特阿拉伯？
It's like, you know, Gad Saad, who's this guy at Concordia who is in a business school so he can actually say what he thinks now and then,
就像，你知道，加德·萨德，这个在康考迪亚大学的家伙，他在商学院，所以他现在能偶尔说出自己的想法，
he tweeted yesterday, well, he tweeted to the Women's March,
他昨天发推特，发给妇女大游行，
because there's a little Twitter thing, you could do that, I suppose, for the organizers,
因为有个小推特活动，我想是给组织者的，
and he said, why don't you go to the Middle East and have a nice march against Saudi Arabia and see, see how that works out for you.
他说，为什么你们不去中东，在沙特阿拉伯举行一次美好的游行，看看结果如何。
It's like, so you think, well, why not?
就像，所以你会想，为什么不呢？
Like why not?
为什么不呢？
Why are the why are there radical leftists who are so much for rights everywhere?
为什么有那么多激进的左派人士这么支持各地的权利？
That's what they say
这是他们所说的
Why aren't they complaining about Saudi Arabia, for example, which you know breeds a particularly pathological form of ideologically rigid Islam
为什么他们不抱怨沙特阿拉伯，例如，你知道，沙特阿拉伯孕育了一种特别病态的形式的意识形态僵化的伊斯兰教
that basically enslaves their women that's to put it properly.
基本上是奴役他们的女性，这是恰当的说法。
It's like why not complain about that?
为什么不抱怨那个呢？
Well, how about this the enemy of my enemy is my friend
那么，这个怎么样：我的敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
and so when push comes to shove, you see how much concern there is among the radical feminists for the rights of women.
所以，当事情到了关键时刻，你会看到激进女权主义者对女性权利有多少关心。
It's like if the pushing those rights forward doesn't also at the same time undermine the Western patriarchy,
就像如果推动这些权利的同时，没有破坏西方的父权制，
then we'll take the undermining and leave the damn rights behind.
那么我们就先选择破坏，把该死的权利留在后面。
And so there's an insight for you about exactly what's going on at the bottom of all this.
所以，这给你一个洞察，了解这一切背后究竟发生了什么。
So okay, so then there's another weird thing, and I've already sort of hit on it tangentially.
那么好吧，还有另一个奇怪的事情，我已经有点间接提到了。
It's like, well, the postmodernists don't believe in grand unifying narratives,
就像，后现代主义者不相信宏大的统一叙事，
they don't believe in narratives at all, they don't care about value, because they never noticed that you have to value something in order to have some hope in life, right?
他们根本不相信叙事，他们不在乎价值，因为他们从未注意到你必须在生活中有所追求才能有希望，对吧？
Because when you value something, you're pursuing it, and in the pursuit, that's where the meaning in life is, you know, because the rest of it's suffering.
因为当你追求某样东西时，你正在追寻它，在追寻中，那里才是生活的意义，你知道，因为其他的都是苦难。
If you're trying to struggle upwards towards the light, it's like, well, that's something to motivate you and to protect you against the suffering.
如果你正在努力向光明处挣扎，那么，这就是激励你并保护你免受苦难的东西。
But the postmodernists don't care about any of that, and I would say it's because they don't care about suffering.
但后现代主义者不在乎这些，我会说这是因为他们不在乎苦难。
So all right, so here, but here's the, here's the final question.
好的，这里是，但这是最后的问题。
It's like, well, if the postmodernists don't care about grand unifying narratives and they don't believe in identity,
就像，如果后现代主义者不关心宏大统一的叙事，他们不相信身份，
why in the world are they willing to believe in gender identity and sexual identity and racial identity and ethnic identity.
为什么他们愿意相信性别身份、性取向身份、种族身份和民族身份。
And the answer to that is, well, they can't.
答案是，他们不能。
But they don't care, because coherence isn't on their agenda.
但他们不在乎，因为一致性不在他们的议程上。
And besides that, when push comes to shove, their postmodernism is nested inside a deeper Marxism,
此外，当推动事态发展时，他们的后现代主义嵌套在更深层的Marxism主义内，
and so when the postmodern narrative doesn't suffice, say, to push forward the idea that Western civilization should be overturned,
所以当后现代叙事不足以推进西方文明应该被推翻的想法时，
they just revert back to the overarching Marxism and say well those people are oppressed and that's a bad thing
他们就回退到更广泛的Marxism主义，说那些人被压迫了，这是坏事
it's like you might say, well you're a post-modernist it's like you don't believe in any of that
你可能会说，嗯，你是个后现代主义者，你不相信任何那些
they say, well yeah I'm only a post-modernist this deep
他们说，嗯，是的，我只是表面上是后现代主义者
but underneath that there's a Marxism and I can always rely on that to fill in the gaps
但在那下面有一个Marxism主义，我总是可以依靠它来填补空白
and that's exactly what's happening so so that's what's happening as far as I can tell
这正是正在发生的事情，所以这就是我能看到的情况
and you know so why do I believe this well there's a little war going on in our culture
你知道，那么我为什么相信这个，嗯，我们的文化中正在进行一场小小的战争
maybe it's not so little I put my finger on it and I wouldn't recommend that by the way
也许它并不小，我指出了它，顺便说一句，我不推荐这样做
because okay you explain it man you explain why like three million people have watched the U of T free speech rally
因为好吧，你来解释吧，你解释为什么像三百万人观看了多伦多大学的言论自由集会
and I think seven million people downloaded the Jill Rogan podcast
我认为有七百万人下载了Joe Rogan播客
and it's like crazy it's crazy there was a hundred and eighty newspaper articles about this it was news for four months
这简直疯狂，这疯狂，有一百八十篇报纸文章报道了这个，这是四个月的新闻
why who cares what I think god I don't I don't even care that much about what I think.
为什么，谁在乎我怎么想，天哪，我甚至都不那么在乎我自己的想法。
What about Trump?
特朗普怎么样？
What's going on there?
那里发生了什么？
What's going on there, exactly?
确切地说，那里发生了什么？
You know, it was interesting listening to Trump's inauguration speech, because
你知道，听特朗普的就职演讲很有趣，因为我在其中察觉到了National Socialist思想的元素。
You know, I'm not being dismissive.
你知道，我不是在轻视。
I'm seriously not being dismissive.
我真的不是在轻视。
But, when you radically activate on the side of the left,
但是，当你在左翼方面激进行动时，
you call forth compensatory forces.
你就会召唤出补偿性力量。
And they're not in your control and like Trump opened his speech you just read it.
它们不受你控制，就像你刚读的特朗普开场白那样。
It's he sounds like a 1950 socialist
他听起来像一个1950年代的社会主义者
You know he's gonna use the power of the state to bring the industry home to produce a lot of infrastructure
你知道他会使用国家的力量把产业带回国内，建设大量的基础设施
It's a state business unity with the state in charge, and then at the end of his speech
这是国家与企业的统一，国家掌控一切，然后在他的演讲结束时
Which is where he stops being at least the international kind of socialist He says well borders are really important and so is national identity
这是他停止成为至少是国际类型的社会主义者的地方，他说边界非常重要，国家认同也是如此
he does embed that it within belief in God which is probably a good thing assuming that he's serious about that,
他确实在上帝信仰之内嵌入了这一点，假设他对此是认真的，这可能是好事，
but the fact that Trump was elected in the end that there was such a fight between him and the Clintonites
但特朗普最终被选举和他与克林顿阵营之间的斗争事实
and that the Clintonites were playing identity politics instead of speaking for the working class who then Trump co-opted like he should have
以及克林顿阵营玩弄身份政治而不是代表工人阶级，然后特朗普像他应该的那样吸纳了他们
There there's a war going on there, and then well what about Brexit?
那里正在进行一场战争，那么，英国脱欧怎么样？
What's going on there, and what about France with Marine Le Pen and what about Holland with Wilders?
那里发生了什么，法国的玛丽娜·勒庞又如何，荷兰的维尔德斯呢？
You know watch it We're in a chaotic time and you know I've got letters from people all over the world
你知道的，我们正处在一个混乱的时期，而且我收到了来自世界各地人们的信件
who tell me how they can't say what they think it's like Oh, well, that's not very good and they're kind of happy with me
他们告诉我他们无法说出他们的想法，这就像，哦，这不太好，他们因为我而感到高兴
because maybe they think that I emboldened them in some way And so good good for that
因为也许他们认为我以某种方式鼓舞了他们，那么这很好
Hypothetically and most of the people who wrote me the overwhelming majority were reasonable So pretty happy about that too,
从假设上讲，写信给我的大部分人都很理智，我对此也感到很高兴。
but and maybe I'm wrong about my damn diagnosis because like what do I know?
但也许我对我的判断错了，因为我又怎么能确切知道呢？
I know, but I do have this proclivity to get to the bottom of things.
我知道，但我确实有探究事物深处的倾向。
And what's at the bottom of this is an ideological war, or a philosophical war, it's even deeper than that.
而事物深处的是一场意识形态战争，或者哲学战争，它甚至比这更深。
It might even be deeper than a philosophical war, which is something that's more like a metaphysical or a theological war.
它可能比哲学战争还要深，这是某种更像是形而上学或神学战争。
You know, it depends on how far down you look, and the postmodernists know exactly what they're doing.
你知道，这取决于你看得有多深，而后现代主义者们确切地知道他们在做什么。
This isn't accidental.
这不是偶然的。
Of course you shut down speakers you don't agree with, because you can't have a dialogue with a man anyways,
当然你会关闭那些你不同意的演讲者，因为你无法与一个人进行对话，
because human beings can't have dialogue.
因为人类无法进行对话。
There's no such thing as a human individual.
没有所谓的个体人类。
There's no such thing as truth.
没有所谓的真理。
Here's the postmodern world.
这就是后现代世界。
It's the Hobbesian nightmare.
这是霍布斯的噩梦。
It's everyone against everyone else, except it's not individuals, it's groups.
这是每个人都与每个人对立，除了不是个体对立，而是群体对立。
And you're stuck in your damn group, and it's the only thing about you anyways that's relevant,
而你被困在你的该死群体中，这是关于你的唯一相关的事情，
which is why we might base our hiring on it, for example.
例如，这就是为什么我们可能会以此为基础进行招聘。
And you're oppressed, and even if you don't know it, it's only because you've internalized it,
你受到压迫，即使你不知道，那只是因为你已经内化了，
and it's the only thing that's real about you anyways.
这是关于你的唯一真实的事情。
And I can't talk to you because I'm in my own little silo of privileged belief.
而我不能和你交谈，因为我处在我自己的小小的特权信念中。
And besides, we can't use logic because that doesn't exist.
而且，我们不能使用逻辑，因为那不存在。
And so you're in a group, and I'm in a group, and all we can do is have a war.
所以你在一个群体中，我在一个群体中，我们所能做的就是战争。
Or we can talk, but we don't get to talk, because you can't talk if you're a postmodernist, because speech is just chatter.
或者我们本可以交流，但我们又无法交流，因为如果你是一个后现代主义者，你不相信交流，因为言语只是闲聊。
So it's just chatter that supports the people in power.
所以这只是支持掌权者的闲聊。
That's how they think.
那就是他们的想法。
So the whole world is this little armed war of identity group against identity group against identity group.
所以整个世界就是这样一个小小的武装战争，一个身份群体对抗另一个身份群体。
And you shut down people who don't agree with you because why should you let them talk?
而你关闭那些不同意你观点的人，因为你为什么要让他们说话呢？
You don't believe in any of the reasons why you would let someone talk.
你不相信任何让某人说话的理由。
So this isn't accidental.
所以这不是偶然的。
It's not because they're afraid, although it's also because of that.
这不是因为他们害怕，虽然也是因为那样。
They hijack, you know, fear.
他们劫持了，你知道，恐惧。
They hijack compassion.
他们劫持了同情。
They make anyone who puts forward an alternative view into a terrorist of ideas, and someone who's heartless at the core,
他们让任何提出另类观点的人成为思想恐怖分子，以及内心冷酷的人，
which is really incredibly intelligent, it's such a good strategy.
这真的是非常聪明，是一个很好的策略。
It's so devious and brilliant, and it's so effective, because who the hell wants to be labeled a bigot?
这是如此狡猾而且聪明，而且非常有效，因为谁愿意被标记为偏执狂呢？
You probably are a damn bigot, just like everyone else.
你可能真的是个该死的偏执狂，就像其他所有人一样。
So you know, when it's easy to make people feel guilty about that, maybe they should.
所以你知道，当让人们因此感到内疚变得很容易时，也许他们应该这样。
anyways what's going on well that's what's going on and so what do you do about it
无论如何，发生了什么，那么这就是发生的事情，那么你该怎么办呢
well I don't know what you do about it but I have a theory and that's one I've been working on for like 40 years
我不知道你该怎么办，但我有一个理论，这是我研究了大约40年的
so one of the problems with post-modernism and I'm gonna take five minutes and then we're done one of the problems with post-modernism is that
所以后现代主义的问题之一，我将花五分钟然后我们就结束，后现代主义的问题之一是
and this is a big problem like this is a fatal problem apart from the fact that it's incoherent
这是一个大问题，这是一个致命的问题，除了它是不一致的
and there's no value structure in it and it's fundamentally divisive and destructive there's a a logical problem with it, too, that's even worse.
它里面没有价值结构，它根本上是分裂性和破坏性的，还有一个逻辑问题，更糟。
And so you might be noticing that the LGBT set of acronyms keeps growing, eh?
所以你可能注意到LGBT的首字母缩写词组不断增长，是吧？
And it's kind of a form of its own parody in some sense.
在某种意义上，这有点像它自己的讽刺。
It's like, well, I'm oppressed.
就像，嗯，我被压迫了。
It's like, yeah, yeah, you are.
就像，是的，是的，你被压迫了。
And well, I'm oppressed, too.
嗯，我也被压迫了。
Yeah, you're also oppressed, and maybe I'm even impressing you being part of this other marginalized group, but at least we share our oppression.
是的，你也被压迫了，也许我作为这个其他边缘化群体的一部分，甚至在压迫你，但至少我们分享了我们的压迫。
Well, so am I. I'm oppressed, too.
嗯，我也是。我也被压迫了。
It's like, okay, so here's a problem.
就像，好吧，这里有个问题。
a big problem here.
这是个大问题。
The problem is it's true.
问题是这是真的。
You're oppressed, you're oppressed, you're oppressed, you're oppressed.
你受压迫，你受压迫，你受压迫，你受压迫。
God only knows why.
只有上帝知道为什么。
Maybe you're too short or you're not as beautiful as you could be or, you know, your parent, your grandparent was a serf, likely,
也许你太矮，或者你没有你本可以有的那么美，或者，你知道，你的父母，你的祖父母是农奴，很可能，
because almost everybody's grand, great grandparent was.
因为几乎每个人的祖父母都是。
It's like, you know, and you're not as smart as you could be and you have a sick relative and you have your own physical problems
就像，你知道的，你没有你本可以有的那么聪明，你有一个生病的亲人，你有你自己的身体问题
and it's like, frankly, you're a mess and you're oppressed in every possible way,
坦白说，你一团糟，你以所有可能的方式受到压迫，
including your ancestry and your biology and the entire sum of human history has conspired to produce victimized you with all your individual pathological problems
包括你的祖先和你的生物学以及整个人类历史都密谋产生了受害的你，带着你所有的个人病理性的问题
it's like yes true okay but the problem is is that it is true
就像，是的，真的，好吧，但问题是这是真的
and so if you take the oppressed you have to fractionate them and fractionate them
所以如果你考虑受压迫的人，你必须将他们分割，再分割
it's like you're a woman yeah
就像你是个女人，是的
okay well I'm a black woman
好吧，我是个有两个孩子的黑人女性
well I'm a black woman who has two children
好吧，我是个有两个孩子的黑人女性，其中一个孩子健康状况不佳，然后，
I'm a I'm a Hispanic woman and I have a genius son who doesn't have any money
我是个有一个天才儿子但没有钱上大学的西班牙裔女性，所以他没有办法上大学
I had a hell of a time getting across the border It was really hard on me to get my citizenship.
我过境时遇到了很多困难，获得公民身份对我来说真的很艰难。
My husband is an alcoholic brute.
我的丈夫是个酗酒的暴徒。
It's like well, yeah, that sucks, too
就像，好吧，是的，那也很糟糕
And so well, so let's let's let's fix all your oppressive oppression
那么，让我们来解决你所有的压迫问题吧
And we'll take every single thing into account and then we'll fix yours, too We'll take every single thing into account.
我们会考虑到每一件事，然后我们也会解决你的问题，考虑到每一件事。
It's like no you won't because you can't you can't it is
但，不，你不会的，因为你做不到，你做不到，这是
Technically impossible first of all you can't even list all the ways that you're oppressed second.
首先，技术上不可能，你甚至无法列出所有你受到的压迫方式。
How are you gonna weight them?
第二，你怎么给它们权重？
Third who's gonna decide and that's the bloody thing who's gonna decide.
第三，谁来决定？那就是血腥的事，谁来决定。
That's the thing well What's the answer in the West it's like in free markets?
这就是问题所在，西方自由市场的答案是什么？
Oh?
哦？
Yeah, Christ will never be able to solve this problem And no one can solve it.
是的，基督永远无法解决这个问题，没有人能解决。
What are we going to do about that?
我们要怎么办呢？
We're going to outsource it to the marketplace.
我们要把它外包给市场。
You're going to take your sorry, pathetic being, and you're going to try to offer me something that maybe I want.
你会接受你的抱歉、可悲的存在，并且你会尝试为我提供一些我可能想要的东西。
And I'm going to take my sorry, pathetic being, and I'm going to say, well, all things considered,
我要接受我的抱歉、可怜的存在，我要说，好吧，考虑到所有事情，
as well as I can understand them, maybe I could give you this much money, which is actually a promise, for that thing.
就我所能理解的，也许我可以给你这么多钱，这实际上是一种承诺，换取那个东西。
And you've packed all of your damn oppression into the price.
你把你所有的该死压迫都包含在价格里。
And I've packed all my oppression into the willingness to pay it.
而我把我所有的压迫都包含在愿意支付它的意愿中。
And that solution sucks.
而这个解决方案很糟糕。
It's a bad solution.
这是一个糟糕的解决方案。
But compared to every other solution, man, it's why 10% of us have freedom.
但与其他所有解决方案相比，伙计，这就是为什么我们10%的人有自由。
And so there's a tremendous illogic at the bottom of this.
所以，在这一切的底层有着巨大的非逻辑性。
It's like, you have to fractionate the oppressed all the way down to the level of the individual.
就像，你必须将受压迫的人分割到个体层面。
Oh, that's what the West figured out.
哦，这就是西方弄明白的东西。
You know, there's a couple of figures who at the mythological roots of our culture and,
你知道，有一些人物在我们文化的神话根源中，
know people get upset with me because I bring in religious themes
知道人们因为我引入宗教主题而对我感到不满
but I understand some things about mythology and religion it's not an accident that
但我理解一些关于神话和宗教的东西，这不是偶然的
the axiomatic Western individual is someone who was unfairly nailed to a cross and tortured it's like yes right exactly so what do you do about that
西方的基本个体是某个被不公正地钉在十字架上并受折磨的人，就像是的，确切地说，那么你对此怎么办呢
well I thought about that for a long time too it's like well you don't get together in a damn Bob
嗯，我也思考了很长时间，就像嗯，你不要聚在一起成为一个该死的暴民
because all that does is allow you to be as horrible as you could possibly imagine and suffer from none of the consequences
因为那只会让你变得尽可能地可怕，并且不用承担任何后果
that's a bad idea so how about we don't do that well there's a deep idea in the West too
那是个坏主意，那么我们就不要那样做，西方也有一个深刻的想法
It's like pick up your damn suffering and bear it and try to be a good person so you don't make it worse.
就像承担起你该死的苦难，并试着成为一个好人，这样你就不会让事情变得更糟。
Well, that's a truth.
嗯，那是个真理。
You know, I read a lot about the terrible things that people have done to each other.
你知道，我读了很多关于人们彼此做过的可怕事情。
You just cannot even imagine it.
你甚至无法想象。
It's so awful.
这太可怕了。
So you don't want to be someone like that.
所以你不想成为那样的人。
Now, do you have a reason to be?
现在，你有理由成为那样的人吗？
Yes!
是的！
You have a lots of reasons to be.
你有很多理由。
God, there's reasons to be resentful about your existence, everyone you know is going to die, you know?
天哪，有理由对你的存在感到愤怒，你认识的每个人都会死，你知道吗？
You too.
你也会。
And there's going to be a fair bit of pain along the way, and lots of it's going to be unfair.
而且一路上会有相当多的痛苦，其中很多都是不公平的。
It's like, yeah, no wonder you're resentful.
就像，是的，难怪你会感到愤怒。
It's like, act it out and see what happens.
就像，去行动看看会发生什么。
You make everything you're complaining about infinitely worse.
你让你抱怨的一切都变得无限糟糕。
There's this idea that hell is a bottomless pit, and that's because no matter how bad it is,
有这样一个观点，地狱是一个无底洞，那是因为无论情况多么糟糕，
some stupid son of a bitch like you could figure out a way to make it a lot worse.
像你这样的愚蠢的混蛋总能找到方法让它变得更糟。
you think, well, what do you do about that?
你会想，那么你该怎么办呢？
Well, you accept it.
嗯，你接受它。
That's what life is like.
这就是生活。
It's suffering.
这是苦难。
That's what the religious people have always said.
这就是宗教人士一直说的。
Life is
生活就是
suffering.
苦难。
Yes.
是的。
Well, who wants to admit that?
嗯，谁想承认这一点？
Well, just think about it.
嗯，好好想想吧。
Well, so what do you do in the face of that suffering?
那么，在面对这些苦难时你该怎么办？
Try to reduce it.
试着减少它。
Start with yourself.
从你自己开始。
What good are you?
你有什么好处？
Get yourself together, for Christ's sake, so that when your father dies you're not whining away in a corner
把自己整理好，看在上帝的份上，这样当你的父亲去世时你不会在角落里哭泣
and you can help plan the funeral and you can stand up solidly so that people can rely on you that's
你可以帮忙计划葬礼，你可以坚强地站立，这样人们可以依靠你
better don't be a damn victim course you're a victim Jesus obviously put yourself together
更好 不要成为一个该死的受害者 当然你是受害者 耶稣显然 把自己整理好
and then maybe if you put yourself together you know how to do that
然后也许如果你把自己整理好 你知道怎么做
you know what's wrong with you if you'll admit it you know there's a few things you could like polish up a little bit that
你知道自己哪里不对 如果你愿意承认 你知道有几件事你可以稍微改善一下
you might even be able to manage in your insufficient present condition
即使你现在情况过得不好，你也可以去调整它
and so you might shine yourself up a little bit and then your eyes will be a little more open
所以你可能会稍微提升一下自己 然后你的视野会更开阔一些
then you can shine yourself up a little bit more and then maybe you could bring your family together
然后你可以让自己更加光彩 然后也许你能让你的家庭团结起来
instead of having them be the hateful spiteful neurotic infighting batch
而不是让他们成为你注定要和他们一起度过圣诞节的仇恨、怨恨、神经质、内斗的一群人
that you're like doomed to spend Christmas with so then you fix yourself up a little bit kind of humbly because you know God you're a fixer-upper
那么你就稍微修整一下自己 因为你知道 上帝啊 你是个需要修缮的人
if there ever was one and then you got to figure out
如果有的话 然后你得弄清楚
well can you figure out how to make peace with your idiot brother
嗯 你能弄明白怎样与你那愚蠢的兄弟和平相处吗
and probably not because he's just as dumb as you so the how the hell are you gonna manage that
可能不行 因为他和你一样愚蠢 那你要怎么处理这件事呢
and so then you maybe you get somewhere that way and your family sort of functioning and you find out
然后你也许能够找到一些方法 你的家庭开始正常运作 你会发现
well that kind of relieved a little bit of suffering although it reduced the opportunities for spiteful revenge
嗯 这样稍微减轻了一些苦难 尽管它减少了报复的机会
and that's kind of a pain in the neck and so then you get your family together a little bit
这也有点麻烦 所以然后你让你的家庭稍微团结一点
and you're a little clued in then, at least a bit, because you've done something difficult that's actually difficult.
至少你有点线索 因为你做了一些真正困难的事情。
You're a little wiser, and so then maybe you could put a tentative finger out beyond the family
你变得更智慧了，然后也许你可以试着伸出一根试探性的手指，超越家庭
and try to change some little thing without wrecking it.
尝试改变一些小事物而不是破坏它。
It's like, our society is complex, and we teach our students that they could just fix it.
我们的社会是复杂的，我们教导我们的学生他们可以简单地修复它。
It's like, go fix a military helicopter and see how far you get with that.
就像，去修理一架军用直升机，看看你能走多远。
It's like, you know what you're going to do?
你知道你会做什么吗？
You're like a chimp with a wrench.
你就像是一个拿着扳手的黑猩猩。
Whack!
砰！
Oh, look!
哦，看！
It's better!
变好了！
It's like, no!
就像，不！
It's not better.
它没有变好。
Things are complicated.
事情很复杂。
And to fix things is really hard.
修复事物真的很难。
And you have to be like a golden tool to fix things.
你必须像黄金工具一样才能修复事物。
And you're not.
而你不是。
So – and that's the other message of the West.
所以——这也是西方的另一个主要思想。
It's like, how do you overcome the suffering of life?
就像，你如何克服生活的苦难？
And I'm not saying it's only the message of the West.
我不是说这只是西方的思想。
How do you overcome the suffering of life?
你如何克服生活的苦难？
Be a better person.
成为一个更好的人。
That's how you do it.
这就是你该怎么做的。
Well, that's hard takes responsibility
嗯，这很难，需要承担责任
and I think you said to someone you want to have a meaningful life everything you do matters that's the definition of a meaningful life
我认为，你对某人说过，你想要过有意义的生活，你所做的一切都很重要，这就是有意义的生活的定义
but everything you do matters you're gonna have to carry that with you or do you want to just forget about the whole meaning thing and then you don't have any responsibility
但既然你的每一件事都重要，你就得承担这个重量。还是你想要把所有关于意义的事情都抛在脑后，从而不承担任何责任呢？
because who the hell cares and you can wander through life doing whatever you want gratifying impulsive desires for how useful that's going to be.
因为谁在乎呢？你也可以在生活中游荡，做任何你想做的事，满足冲动的欲望，看看那会不会有用。
And you're stuck in meaninglessness, but you don't have any responsibility.
你陷入了无意义的境地，但你没有任何责任。
Which one do you want?
你想要哪一个？
Well, ask yourself, which one are you pursuing?
问问自己，你在追求哪一个？
And you'll find very rapidly that it isn't the majority of your soul that's pursuing the whole meaning thing, because, well, look what you have to do to do that.
你会很快发现，你灵魂的大部分并没有在追求生活的深层意义和目的，因为，嗯，看看为了做到这一点你需要做什么，
You have to take on the fact that life is suffering.
你必须接受生活就是苦难的事实。
You have to put yourself together in the face of that.
面对这一点，你必须把自己整合起来。
Well, that's hard.
嗯，那很难。
Christ it's amazing people can even do it
天哪，人们甚至能做到这一点真是不可思议
I'm stunned every day when I go outside
每天我走出门都感到惊讶
And it isn't a riot with everything burning because really God you talk to people it's like I knew this guy
并不是一场骚乱，一切都在燃烧，因为真的，上帝啊，你和人们交谈，就像我认识的一个人
he'd been in a motorcycle accident, and it really ruined him and he was like a linesman working on the power
他遭遇了一场摩托车事故，这真的毁了他，他是一个在电力公司工作的架线员
and he was working with someone who had Parkinson's disease, and they had complementary inadequate seas
他和一个患有帕金森病的人一起工作，他们有互补的不足
and so two of them could do the job of one person and so they're out there fixing power lines in the freezing cold
所以他们两个人可以完成一个人的工作，他们在冰冷的天气里修理电线
despite the fact that one was three-quarters wrecked with a motorcycle accident the other one had Parkinson's
尽管一个人因摩托车事故几乎完全毁了，另一个人患有帕金森病
it's like that's how our civilization works it's like there's all these ruined people out there they've got problems like you can't believe off
这就是我们的文明的运作方式，外面有那么多被毁掉的人，他们面临着你无法相信的问题
they go to work and do things they don't even like and look the lights are on my my God, it's unbelievable, it's a miracle, it's a miracle.
他们去工作，做他们甚至不喜欢的事情，看，光还在，我的天哪，这简直不可思议，这是个奇迹，是个奇迹。
And we're so ungrateful, college students, the post-modern types, they're so ungrateful.
我们是如此的不知感恩，大学生们，后现代类型的人，他们是如此的不知感恩。
You know, they don't know that they're surrounded by just a bloody miracle, it's a miracle that all this stuff works,
你知道，他们不知道他们被一个彻头彻尾的奇迹所包围，这一切都能运作真是个奇迹，
that all you crazy chimpanzees that don't know each other can sit in the same room for two hours sweltering away without tearing each other apart,
你们这些互不相识的疯狂黑猩猩可以在同一个房间里闷热地坐两个小时而不会把彼此撕碎，
because that's what chimps do so anyways so what happened well I made some videos
因为黑猩猩就是这么做的。所以，发生了什么呢？我制作了一些视频
and I got to the bottom of some things at least as far as I can tell so I told you what the bottom is
我至少弄清楚了一些事情，所以我告诉了你们底层是什么
and then I've got this idea about what you might do about it which isn't my idea it's like it's not my idea
然后我有了一个关于你可能怎么做的想法，这不是我的想法，它不是我的想法
it's an old old old old idea it's far older than Christianity
这是一个古老的古老的古老的想法，远比基督教还要古老
it's the oldest story of mankind get yourself together transcend your suffering see if you can be some kind of hero make the suffering in the world less
这是人类最古老的故事，让自己变得更完善，超越你的苦难，看看你是否能成为某种英雄，让世界上的苦难减少
well that's the way forward as far as I can tell if there is any way forward and that's what's under assault by the postmodernists
嗯，那是向前迈进的方式，据我所知，如果有任何向前迈进的方式，那就是它，而这正是被后现代主义者攻击的
so look out because they know exactly what they're doing and they know exactly why they're doing it and that's what it looks like to me so that's it
所以小心，因为他们确切知道他们在做什么，他们确切知道他们为什么这么做，对我来说，就是这样，就这些了。